Guide to the Administrative Papers of the Chancellor Harry Woodburn Chase 1933-1951 RG.3.0.5
New York University Archives
- Series II: Administrative Correspondence
  - Institute on Federal Taxation, 1942-1950 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Institute of International Finance, 1926-1945 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Institute of Labor Relations & Social Security, 1948-1951 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Institute of Meteorology, 1932-1934 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Institute of PublicLaw & Administration (Discontinued, 1945), 1939-1941 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - James, Professor Phillip (Professor of Music), 1935-1942 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - James Arthur Collection of Clocks & Watches Lecture Series, 1933-1950 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Johnson, Dr. Robert Underwood (Director, Hall of Fame), 1930-1938 (Box 49, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Judson Dormitory, Integration of, 1940-1945 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Junior College Plans, 1934-1941 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Kimball, Dr. Fiske (University Architect), 1933-1947 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Klemin, Professor Alexander (Professor of Aeronautical Engineering), 1933-1941 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Korzybski, Count Alfred, 1934 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Labor Relations, Committee on, 1944-1950 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Law, School of, 1943-1951 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Law, School of: Board of Visitors, 1944-1945 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Law, School of: Deanship, 1940-1948 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Law, School of: Proposed Dinner, 1946 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Liberal Education in America (American Mercury article, 1934), 1944 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Libraries, Council Committee on: General Business, 1933-1934 (Box 49, Folder 14 - 15)
  - Libraries, Council Committee on: Meeting Material, 1933-1934 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Libraries, Director of - Robert Downs, 1937-1950 (Box 50, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Libraries, Faculty Committee on, 1936 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Library, Washington Square, 1934-1935 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Loomis, Dean Milton E. (Washington Square College), 1934-1936 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Loomis, Dean Milton E., 1937-1940 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Lott, James H. (Manager of New York University Commons and Bookstore), 1934-1943 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - MacCracken, John H. (Son of Chancellor Maccracken), May 1936-Dec 1936 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Madden, John T. (Dean of the School of Commerce, Accounts, and Finance), 1934-1948 (Box 50, Folder 9 - 10)
  - Mayor's Committee on Unity, 1945-1947 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - McEwen, Dean Currier (New York University College of medicine), 1943-1950 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Medical Center, 1948 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Medicine, College of, 1934-1937 (Box 51, Folder 2 - 3)
  - Medicine, College of, 1938-1939 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Medicine, College of, 1940 (Box 51, Folder 5 - 6)
  - Medicine, College of (includes picture of Somerset Maugham), 1941-1942 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Medicine, college of, 1943-1944 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Medicine, College of, 1945-1950 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Medicine, College of, 1941-1943 (Box 52, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Middle States Association: Correspondence, 1948-1950 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Middle States Association: Correspondence, Apr 1950-Dec 1950 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Middle States Association: Digests and reports, 1948-1950 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Messages, Miscellaneous for Dr. Chase, 1943-1950 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Motion Picture Research Council, ca.1943 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Museum of Music, 1938-1940 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Musser, John (Professor of History; Executive Secretary of the Graduate School), 1934-1949 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - National Recovery Act, 1933 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - National War Fund, 1943 (Box 52, Folder 11 - 12)
  - National War Fund, 1944-1946 (Box 53, Folder 1 - 2)
  - National Youth Administration, 1935-1942 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Naval Awards, 1946-1948 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - New (Experimental Junior) College Plan, 1934 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Newark, University of, 1936-1940 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Newman, Allen T. (Dean of the College of Dentistry), 1929-1940 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper, Student (All-University), 1933-1934 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - S.S. "NYU Victory", 1944-1945 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Nichols, William H., Bust of, 1941 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Nobel Prize Dinner, 1944-1945 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Ostberg, Ragnor (Swedish architect), Luncheon for, 1934 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Ottendorfer Memorial Fellowship Committee, 1934-1940 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Pabst Co. - Centenary Manuscript, 1944-1948 (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Paris, W. Francklyn (honorary Director of the Hall of American Artists at NYU), 1932-1949 (Box 53, Folder 15 - 16)
  - Park, Joseph H. (Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences and Chairman of the, 1941-1950 (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - Department of History), undated (Box 53)
  - Phelps Lectures (Stokes Foundation), 1915-1932 (Box 54, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Phelps Lectures (Stokes Foundation), 1933-1942 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Phelps Lectureship, 1940-1941 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Pickett, Ralph E. (Secretary of the Faculty and Assistant Dean of the School of Education), 1935-1941 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Placement Facilities, 1939-1941 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Planning Committee of the Council, 1934-1935 (Box 54, Folder 7 - 9)
  - Planning Committee of the Council: - Wall Street Poject, Graduate School, undated (Box 54, Folder 10 - 11)
  - of Business Administration (GBA), 1934-1937 (Box 54)
  - -Wall Street Project, (GBA), 1937-1938 (Box 54, Folder 12 - 13)
  - Preliminary Report with Respect to Graduate Work, 1950 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Press, NYU - Committee on Management, 1933-1934 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Provost's Office - Confidential Report, n.d., undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Psychological Test Service, 1936-1938 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Public Works of Art Project, 1934 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Quarterly (All-University), 1936-1937 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Residence (Course) Credit, 1939-1940 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Retailing, School of, 1930-1940 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Retailing, School of, 1940-1950 (Box 55, Folder 9 - 10)
  - Retailing, School of: Trustees, 1944-1945 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Retailing, School of: Deanship, 1944-1946 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Reserve Fund, 1938-1947 (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Reserve Officer Training Corp (R.O.T.C.), 1933-1935 (Box 55, Folder 14 - 15)
  - R.O.T.C., 1936-1937 (Box 56, Folder 1 - 2)
  - R.O.T.C., 1938-1941 (Box 56, Folder 3 - 4)
  - R.O.T.C., 1942-1943 (Box 56, Folder 5 - 6)
  - Radio: Radio Projects at NYU, 1936-1938 (Box 56, Folder 7-8)
  - Radio: Radio Projects at NYU, 1939-1941 (Box 56, Folder 9 - 10)
  - Radio: Radio Materials, Miscellaneous, 1936 (Box 57, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Radio: Radio Materials, Miscellaneous, 1937-1938 (Box 57, Folder 3 - 4)
  - Radosavljevich, Milenko (son of Paul R.Radosavljevich), 1944-1949 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Relief Work at NYU (Student and Others), 1934-1935 (Box 57, Folder 6 - 7)
  - Rent Gouging - NYU, 1944 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Rice, Paul North (Director of Libraries), 1936-1938 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1939-1948 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Russell, Bertrand - City College Appointment Case, 1940 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Salin Library, transfer of, to NYU, 1934-1935 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Sanitary Engineering Building, 1935-1936 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Saville, Thorndike (Dean of the College of Engineering, 1935-1950 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Sawhill, Dr. John E. (University physician), 1935-1950 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Sheldon, H. Horton (Professor of Physics), 1939-1940 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Shepard, Mrs. Finley J. (Helen Miller Gould), 1933 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Smith, Rufus D. (Provost), 1933-1950 (Box 58, Folder 7 - 12)
  - Sommer, Frank H. (Dean of the School of Law), 1935-1947 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Speer, Robert K. (Professor of Education), 1933-1944 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Stoker, James J. (Professor of Mathematics), 1944-1945 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Student Organization and Publications, 1933-1944 (Box 59, Folder 4 - 10)
  - Survey: Degrees Conferred at NYU, 1930-1935 (Box 60, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Survey: Economics at NYU, 1934-1935 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Survey: Graduate Study at NYU, 1934-1935 (Box 60, Folder 4 - 5)
  - Tauritz, Leo L., 1938-1950 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Temporary Emergency Relief Administration, 1934-1935 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Testing and Advisement Center, 1950-1951 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Townsend Harris High School, 1942 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - President Truman, Letter to, 1945 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Universities Research Center for the United Nations, 1946-1947 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - University College of Arts and Pure Science, 1935-1938 (Box 60, Folder 12 - 13)
  - University College of Arts and Pure Science, 1939-1943 (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - University College of Arts and Pure Science, 1944-1950 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - University Heights, 1946-1947 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Visiting Committee for University Heights (Arts and Engineering), 1942 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Visiting Committees for University Heights (Arts and Engineering), 1946-1950 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Voorhis, Harold 0. (Vice Chancellor and Secretary), 1945-1950 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Warburg House, 1935-1937 (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Washington Square Area - Planning Recommendations, 1946 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Washington Square College, 1936-1950 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Washington Square College: Curriculum Revision, 1934-1936 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Deanship, 1945-1946 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Deanship, 1947 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Deanship, 1946 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Deanship, 1945-1946 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Deanship, 1945-1947 (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Deanship, 1946 (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Deanship, 1945-1946 (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Deanship, 1945-1946 (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Washington Square College: - Deanship, 1945-1946 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Washington Square College, undated (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Washington Square College, 1934 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Washington Square East Proposal for New Building, 1936 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Washington Square Park Alterations, 1939-1940 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Washington Square Property: - 29-30 Waverly Place and 100 Washington Square East, 1938 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Westchester Center of New York University, 1935-1937 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Westchester Center of New York University, 1946-1948 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Who's Who in America, 1935-1938 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Winning, Freda J. G. (Assistant Professor of Education, Department of Home Economics), 1939 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Wisconsin, University of, 1931-1933 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Works Progress Administration, 1936-1940 (Box 63, Folder 1 - 2)
  - World's Fair, 1935-1938 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - World's Fair, 1939-1940 (Box 63, Folder 4 - 5)
  - Zorbaugh, Harvey (Associate Professor of Education and Director oftheClinicforSocialAdjustmentoftheGifted), 1934-1935 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - SeriesIII:Memberships, undated (Box 63)
- Series III: Memberships
  - Membership: A-A1, 1936-1950 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Membership: Am, 1934-1951 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - American Committee for Christian German Refugees: Correspondence, 1934-1939 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - American Committee for Christian German Refugees: Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - American Committee for Christian German Refugees: Correspondence, 1940-1947 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - American Committee for Christian German Refugees: Special Campaign, 1939 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - American Committee for a Free and United Europe: -Correspondence, 1945 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - 1948-1951, undated (Box 64)
  - American Council on Education - Correspondence, 1935-1948 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - American Scholar, 1934-1941 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - American Memorial to Six Million Jews, 1947-1948 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Memberships: An-Az, 1934-1936, 1942-1944 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Army Advisory Committee, 1947-1950 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Memberships: B, 1934-1950 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - British War Relief, 1940-1941 (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Bronx Affiliations, 1933-1941, 1948 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Memberships: Ca-Cn, 1934-1942, 1946-1950 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Calendar Reform, 1946-1947 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Century Club, 1936-1950 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Certificates and Honors, 1934-1937, 1943-1950 (Box 65, Folder 4 - 5)
  - Church Club, 1936, 1941-1950 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Church Society for College Work, 1935-1940 (Box 65, Folder 7 - 8)
  - Churchman, The, 1939-1946 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Memberships: Co-Cz, 1934-1942 (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Commerce and Industry Association (formerly The Merchants' Association of New York), 1937-1946 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Committee on the Older Worker (U.S. Dept. of Labor): Correspondence, Feb 1938-Mar 1938 (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Committee on the Older Worker (U.S. Dept. of Labor): Correspondence, Apr 1938-Dec 1938 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - -Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Memberships: D, 1936, 1940-1950 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Memberships: E, 1935-1948 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Memberships: F, 1933-1948 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Memberships: G, 1934-1949 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Memberships: H, 1934-1940, 1945-1948 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Hoover Commission Report, Committees on behalf of, 1949-1950 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Hundred Year Association, 1944-1951 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Memberships: I, 1933-1938, 1943-1944, 1948-1951 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Israel Orphan Asylum, 1933-1950 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Memberships: J, 1936, 1940-1950 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Memberships: K, 1934, 1938-1947 (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Memberships: L, 1933-1939, 19441944 (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Lotos Club: Correspondence, 1934-1937 (Box 67, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Lotos Club: Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 67, Folder 3 - 4)
  - Lotos Club: Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 67, Folder 5 - 6)
  - Lotos Club: Correspondence, 1939-1941 (Box 67, Folder 7 - 8)
  - Lotos Club: Correspondence, 1941-1943 (Box 68, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Lotos Club: Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 68, Folder 3 - 5)
  - Lotos Club: Correspondence, 1944-1947 (Box 68, Folder 6 - 8)
  - Lotos Club: Correspondence, 1947-1951 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Luxembourg, Mar 1936-Jul 1939 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Memberships: M, 1933-1943, 1948 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Marshall Plan, 1947 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Mayor's Committees (Various), 1938-1942, 1948 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Memorial Hospital: Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 69, Folder 6 - 7)
  - Memorial Hospital: Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 69, Folder 8 - 9)
  - Metropolitan Opera Association: Correspondence, 1940-1947 (Box 69, Folder 10 - 11)
  - Metropolitan Opera Association: Correspondence, 1947-1951 (Box 70, Folder 1 - 3)
  - Metropolitan Opera Association: Opera House Problem, Reports and Studies Concerning, 1950 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Metropolitan Opera Association: Rehabilitation and New House Committee: Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 70, Folder 5 - 6)
  - Metropolitan Opera Association: Rehabilitation and New House Committee: Memorandum, Mar 1950 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Memberships: Na-Nd, 1933-1950 (Box 71, Folder 1 - 2)
  - National Civil Service League, 1944-1945 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - National Jewish Hospital at Denver, 1939, 1947-1950 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - National Defense World War II - Travel Expenses, 1943-1946 (Box 71, Folder 5 - 6)
  - Memberships: Ne-Nz, 1934-1940, 1944, 1950-1951 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - New England Society, 1946-1951 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - New York Academy of Public Education: Correspondence, 1937-1943 (Box 71, Folder 9 - 10)
  - New York Academy of Public Education: Correspondence, 1943-1947 (Box 71, Folder 11 - 12)
  - New York Academy of Public Education: Correspondence, 1947-1951 (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - New York Public Library: Correspondence, 1943-1947 (Box 72, Folder 1 - 2)
  - New York Public Library: Correspondence, 1948-1950 (Box 72, Folder 3 - 4)
  - New York War and Peace Memorial Committee, 1946-1949 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Memberships: P, 1933-1937, 1941-1945 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Palestine, 1941-1942, 1946-1948 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Alumni in New York, 1937-1946 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Planned Parenthood, National Committee for, 1938-1948 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Memberships: Q-R, 1934-1944, 1948-1949 (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Retail Trade Minimum Wage Board: Correspondence, 1945-1949 (Box 72, Folder 11 - 12)
  - Retail Trade Minimum Wage Board: Briefs, Minutes, Orders, Recommendations, 1945-1946 (Box 73, Folder 1 - 3)
  - Retail Trade Minimum Wage Board: Work Material, 1938-1945 (Box 73, Folder 4 - 6)
  - Russell Sage Foundation: Correspondence, 1936-1947 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Russell Sage Foundation: Correspondence, 1947-1951 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Memberships: Sa-Sl, 1933-1942 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Memberships: Sm-Sz, 1934-1942, 1946-1947 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Memberships: T, 1937-1940, 1945 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Town Hall Inc.: Correspondence, 1935-1942 (Box 74, Folder 4 - 5)
  - Town Hall Inc.: Correspondence, 1942-1947 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Town Hall Inc.: Correspondence, 1947-1951 (Box 74, Folder 7 - 8)
  - TrinityChurch: Correspondence, 1933-1939 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - TrinityChurch: Correspondence, 1939-1942 (Box 74, Folder 10 - 11)
  - TrinityChurch: Correspondence, 1942-1947 (Box 75, Folder 1 - 2)
  - TrinityChurch: Correspondence, 1947-1951 (Box 75, Folder 3 - 4)
  - Memberships: U, 1934-1935, 1939-1950 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - United Negro College Fund, 1944-1949 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  - Universal Military Training, 1947-1948 (Box 75, Folder 7)
  - University Club, 1933-1941, 1945-1950 (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - Memberships: V, 1936-1938 (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - Memberships: W, 1933-1951 (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - War Prisoners Aid, Inc., 1942-1948 (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - Memberships: X, Y, Z, 1938-1941, 1945 (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - YMCA, YWCA, YMHA, etc., 1935-1938 (Box 75, Folder 13)
  - Series IV: Addresses and Published Writings, undated (Box 75)
- Series IV: Adresses and Published Writings
  Scope and Contents note
  Note: Duplicate hardboound copies of Chancellor Chase's addresses and published writings are also available,
  - Bibliography, 1905-1940 (Box 75, Folder 14)
  - Education as Preparation for Tomorrow, published in Think, undated (Box 75, Folder 15)
  - Speeches from Chancellor Chase's old files at the University of Illinois, 1930-1933 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Address and Articles, Index Cards of, 1933-1935 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, 1933 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Convocation Address at NYU, Oct 2, 1933 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Remarks delivered at Luncheon given in chancellor Chase's honor by the Association of Colleges and Universities of the State of New York, Oct 1933 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - The Crisis in Education, address delivered before the Herald Tribune's Women's Conference, Oct 1933 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Address delivered at the New York University Alumni Association Dinner, Oct 1933 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Resolved: That the United States should adopt the essential features of the British system of radio control and operation, radio debate arranged by the National Advisory Council on Radio in Education and the National University Extension Association Debate Committee, Nov 1933 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Statement made by Chancellor Chase at the Association of Urban Universities Dinner, Nov 1933 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - The Administrator and the Testing Program, address delivered before the Educational Records Bureau of the American Council on Education, Nov 1933 (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Armistice Day Address, radio address delivered over the NBC network; sponsored by The League of Remembrance, Nov 11, 1933 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Education Faces the Crisis, address delivered before the Progressive Education Association, Nov 1933 (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Education as a National Resource, address delivered before the Association of Life Insurance Presidents, Dec 8, 1933 (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Chancellor Chase's Addresses, Correspondence re:, 1934 (Box 76, Folder 14)
  - Our Liberal Arts College, published in the AmericanMercury, 1934 (Box 76, Folder 15)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, 1934 (Box 76, Folder 16 - 17)
  - University Freedom, reprinted from the Report of the Chancellor, 1934-1935 (Box 76, Folder 18)
  - This Year of Promise, radio address delivered over the NBC network, Jan 14, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Address delivered at the Dartmouth Alumni Dinner, Jan 18, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - The Responsibility of College Students, address deliveredattheNewmanClubBreakfast, Feb 4, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Address delivered before the Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies, Feb 8, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Our Human Resources, address delivered before the Mid-Winter Trust Conference of the American Bankers Association, Feb 15, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Civilization against Hitlerism, address delivered at Madison Square Garden under the auspices of the American Jewish Congress and Rabbi Stephen S. Wise, Mar 7, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Welcome address delivered at the opening session of the Conference on Handicapped Children and the Conference on Elementary Education, Mar 9, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Popular Education, radio address delivered over the Columbia network on the Program of the National Student Federation, Mar 22, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Address delivered before the College Art Association, Education, a Social Tool, Fifth Annual Davies, Mar 29, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Lecture delivered before the Institute of Arts and Sciences at Columbia University, Apr 18, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 10 - 11)
  - Commencement Address at Lafayette College, Jun 8, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Inaugural Address delivered at the One Hundred and Second Commencement of NYU, Jun 13, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 13)
  - State University: Its Work and Problems, book review published in The Journal of Higher Education, Aug 1934 (Box 77, Folder 14)
  - Crime and the School, address delivered before the Herald Tribune Conference, Sep 26, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 15)
  - Address delivered before the Freshmen of the School of Education, Oct 4, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 16)
  - Address delivered before the Second Michigan Education Association District Meeting, Oct 19, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 17)
  - Education in the Democratic State, address delivered on the Mary Gaston Barnwell Foundation Course, Oct 24, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 18)
  - Address delivered before the Newark Institute and Mercer Beasley Law School, Nov 1, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 19)
  - Thanksgiving Day Service delivered at The Community Church of New York, Nov 29, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 20)
  - The Cultural Value of Art, address delivered before the School Art League, Dec 7, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 21)
  - Radio's Contribution to Education, radio address delivered for the broadcast of The University of the Air, WEVD, Dec 8, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 22)
  - Chancellor Chase's Addresses, Correspondence re:, 1935 (Box 77, Folder 23 - 24)
  - Statements of Chancellor Chase, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Education in the Democratic State, address delivered on October 24, 1934; published in The Barnwell Bulletin, Vol. 12, No. 50, Jan 1935 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Address of tribute delivered at the Memorial Service for Chancellor Brown at First Presbyterian Church, Jan 17, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - A Changing World Confronts the Family, address delivered before the Mother's Club of New Rochelle, Feb 8, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Address delivered at the Annual Dinner of the NYU Law School Alumni Association, Feb 9, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Are the Colleges in Step with the Times? Address delivered before the Beekman Hill Neighbors, Feb 19, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Christian Citizenship, address delivered at the Washington's Birthday Exercises at the, undated (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Cathedral of St. John the Divine, Feb 22, 1935 (Box 78)
  - Address delivered before the New York Electrical Society, Mar 27, 1935 (Box 78, Folder 8)